<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<export>
    <article>
        <author>A. C. Baldry</author>
        <year>2003</year>
        <title>Bullying in schools and exposure to domestic violence</title>
        <rating></rating>
        <journal>Child Abuse &amp; Neglect</journal>
        <tag>Bullying</tag>
        <tag>Domestic violence</tag>
        <tag>Family violence</tag>
        <tag>Intergenerational cycle of abuse</tag>
        <tag>Intergenerational transmission</tag>
        <tag>Intimate partner violence</tag>
        <tag>Victimisation</tag>
        <lastUpdate></lastUpdate>
        <publisher></publisher>
        <placePublished></placePublished>
        <body>Objectives: The study aimed to investigate the relationship between bullying and victimisation in school and exposure to interparental violence in a non-clinical sample of Italian youngsters. Methods: A cross-sectional study was conducted with a sample of 1059 Italian elementary and middle school students. Participants completed a self-report anonymous questionnaire measuring bullying and victimisation and exposure to interparental violence. The questionnaire also included measures on parental child abuse and socio-demographic variables. Results: Almost half of all boys and girls reported different types of bullying and victimisation in the previous 3 months, with boys more involved than girls in bullying others. Exposure to interparental physical violence and direct bullying were significantly associated especially for girls: girls exposed to father's violence against the mother and those exposed to mother's violence against the father were among the most likely to bully directly others compared with girls who had not been exposed to any interparental violence. Hierarchical multiple regression analyses revealed that bullying and victimisation were predicted by exposure to interparental violence, especially mother-to-father violence, over and above age, gender, and child abuse by the father. Conclusions: Exposure to interparental violence is associated with bullying and victimisation in school, even after controlling for direct child abuse. Violence within the family has detrimental effects on the child's behaviour; schools, in this regard, can play a fundamental role in early detection of maladjustment.</body>
        <originalDocument>internal-pdf://Baldry 2003 - Bullying in schools-4183078913/Baldry 2003 - Bullying in schools.pdf</originalDocument>
    </article>
    <article>
        <author>F. Buchanan</author>
        <year>2008</year>
        <title>Mother and infant attachment theory and domestic violence: Crossing the divide</title>
        <rating></rating>
        <journal>Australian Domestic &amp; Family Violence Clearinghouse Stakeholder Papers</journal>
        <tag>Domestic violence</tag>
        <tag>Trauma</tag>
        <lastUpdate></lastUpdate>
        <publisher></publisher>
        <placePublished></placePublished>
        <body>This paper explores how abuse by a father or father figure at the time of birth and during infancy can impact on early mother and infant attachment patterns, and considers the implications for practitioners working with women and infants. It also addresses some ways in which practitioners can assist women to build and repair their infants’ secure attachment patterns, despite the effects of domestic violence.</body>
        <originalDocument>internal-pdf://buchananstakeholder-0383496448/buchananstakeholder.pdf</originalDocument>
    </article>
</export>